Herbert A. Philbrick Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Subject File, 1849-1997 (Box 28-221)
  - Matthews, J. B., 1951-1967, undated, (2 folders)
  - Matusow, Harvey (Box 136)
    - General, 1954-1958, 1985, undated
    - Interview with Al Kahn, 1954, (2 folders)
  - McAvoy, Clifford T., 1952-1954, undated
  - McBirnie, W. S., 1966-1967, 1976, undated
  - McCallum, Edward J., 1960, undated
  - McCarran Act, 1951-1963, undated
  - McCarthy, Eugene J., 1967-1971, undated
  - McCarthy, Joseph R., and McCarthyism, 1950-1972, 1986, undated, (3 folders)
  - McCarthy, Justin, 1959-1963, undated
  - McCloskey, Paul N., 1972, undated
  - McConkey, Betty, 1957, 1965-1969, undated (Box 137)
  - McCord, James, 1973-1974
  - McDowell, Arthur G., 1953-1967, undated, (2 folders)
  - McGovern, George, 1963, 1970-1972, undated
  - McGunnigle, Robert, 1941, 1951-1954, undated
  - McIntire, Carl, 1956-1971, 1991, undated
  - McManus, Robert C., 1953-1958, 1965, undated
  - McNamara, Robert S., 1963-1971
  - McNeil, Thomas J., 1956-1958, undated
  - McWhirter, Felix T., 1964-1971
  - Mead, Margaret, 1966-1970, 1976, 1983, 1989, undated
  - Meany, George, 1955-1956, 1965-1970
  - Medicare, 1962-1967
  - Mediterranean and Eurafrica, 1958
  - Meerloo, Joost A. M., 1957-1960
  - Melish, John Howard, 1951-1953, 1960
  - Melish, William Howard, 1954-1959, undated
  - Mental health, 1955-1963, undated (Box 138)
  - Merrow, Chester E., 1958-1961
  - Methodist Church, 1956-1968, undated
  - Methodist Federation for Social Action, 1939, 1951-1957
  - Methvin, Eugene H., 1970-1971, undated
  - Metro form of government, 1956-1961, undated
  - Mexican-American Bulletin, 1963
  - Mexico, 1963-1971
  - Middle East, 1954-1959, 1967-1975, 1990, undated
  - Mikoyan, Anastas, 1958-1964, undated
  - Miller, Arthur, 1956-1959, 1970, undated
  - Miller, Donald, 1962-1973, undated
  - Miller, Paul and Marion, 1955-1956, 1962-1966, undated
  - Miller, William, 1947-1959, undated
  - Millikan, Max, 1956-1959
  - Milton, Paul R., 1952-1955, undated
  - Minute Women of the United States of America, 1970-1971 (Box 139)
  - Minutemen, 1961-1966, undated, (2 folders)
  - Missiles, 1959-1971
  - Mitchell, John N., 1969-1970
  - Mitchell, Martha, 1970-1971, undated
  - Mlot-Mroz, Jozef, 1959-1970, 1981, undated
  - Moll, George, 1952-1957
  - Monaghan, William E., 1956
  - Monday, Mark, 1964-1965
  - Mooneyham, W. Stanley, 1967
  - Moral leadership guide, 1957
  - Moral Majority, 1983-1987
  - Moral Re-Armament, 1953-1966, undated, (2 folders)
  - Morality in Media, 1969-1978, undated (Box 140)
  - Morford, Elbert S., 1961-1962
  - Morgenthau, Hans, 1965-1967, undated
  - Morris, Robert, 1952-1971, 1985, undated, (2 folders)
  - Morros, Boris, 1957-1963, undated, 1952-1971, 1985, undated
  - Morse, Douglas, 1960-1967, 1982-1983, undated
  - Morse, Wayne, 1954, 1963-1968
  - Mosbacher, David, 1956-1957
  - Moscow News, 1968-1969
  - Mosher, Hollis N., 1959, 1971-1972
  - Motion pictures
    - M & P Theatres, 1942-1949
    - Miscellaneous, 1955-1963, 1971-1989, undated
    - Operation Abolition, 1957-1963, undated, (2 folders)
    - We'll Bury You, 1962, undated (Box 141)
  - Mott, Newcomb, 1966, undated
  - Mott, Stewart, 1969-1972
  - Mowrer, Edgar, 1968-1970
  - Mumford, Lewis, 1936-1937, 1946-1951, 1965, 1990, undated
  - Munson, Lyle H., 1956-1972, undated
  - Murphy, George, 1962-1970, undated
  - Murphy, Maurice J., 1962
  - Muskie, Edmund S., 1970-1971
  - Music, 1952, 1965, 1987, undated
  - Muste, A. J., 1950-1953, 1960-1966, undated
  - My Weekly Reader, 1960, undated
  - Myrdal, Karl Gunnar, 1956-1957, 1967, undated
  - Mysterious deaths
    - Kourdakov, Sergei, 1972-1973, undated
    - Miscellaneous, 1949-1970, 1976, undated
  - Myths and truths about free enterprise, 1961 (Box 142)
  - “M” miscellaneous, 1936, 1949-1976, 1984, undated, (4 folders)
  - NAACP, 1949, 1955-1975, undated
  - Nader, Ralph, 1967-1976, undated
  - Nagy, Imre, 1958-1959, undated
  - Name lists, 1944, 1951-1955, undated
  - Nation, 1952-1962, 1967, undated (Box 143)
  - National Association of Evangelicals, 1959-1968, undated
  - National Broadcasting Co. (NBC), 1952, 1958-1973, undated
  - National Captive Nations Committee, 1960-1967, undated
  - National Citizens Commission for the Public Schools, 1954-1955
  - National Committee for a Free Europe, 1949-1952, 1959, undated, (3 folders)
  - National Committee for a Sane Nuclear Policy (SANE), 1955-1969, 1975, undated, (4 folders)
  - National Congress of Parents and Teachers (PTA) (Box 144)
    - National office, 1962-1966, undated, (6 folders)
    - New Hampshire branch, 1956-1966, undated, (2 folders) (Box 145)
    - United Nations, 1962-1964
  - National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, 1947, 1953-1955, 1968
  - National Council of Churches, 1949-1982, undated See also Container 114, Hruby, Blahoslav, S., (4 folders); (7 folders) (Box 146)
  - National Council of Women of the United States, 1952-1953, undated
  - National Economic Council, 1959-1973, undated
  - National Education Association, 1955-1956, 1963-1966, undated
  - National Education Program, 1953-1973, 1979-1992, undated For additional material see Container 269, same heading, (8 folders) (Box 147)
  - National Exchange Club, 1947-1963, undated, (4 folders) (Box 148)
  - National Farmers' Organization, 1956-1964, undated
  - National Farmers Union, 1949-1959, 1965-1970, undated, (4 folders); (3 folders) (Box 149)
  - National Federation of Independent Business, 1964-1966, undated
  - National Freedom Education Center, King's College, Briarcliff Manor, N. Y., 1961-1969, undated
  - National Guardian, 1952-1953, undated
  - National Institute for Law/Order/Justice, 1969, undated
  - National Lawyers Guild, 1950, 1957-1959, 1968, undated
  - National League of Families of American Prisoners and Missing in Southeast Asia, 1971-1973, undated
  - National Planning Association, undated
  - National Review, 1955-1966, 1972, undated
  - National Rifle Association (NRA), 1966-1973, undated
  - National Right to Work Committee, 1953-1961, undated
  - National States Rights Party, 1960-1966, undated (Box 150)
  - National Student Association, 1963-1969
  - National Youth Alliance, 1969, undated
  - Navy leadership guides, 1958-1966, undated, (3 folders)
  - Nazis, 1954, 1960, 1966, undated For additional material see Container 37, American Nazi Party
  - Nebraska, 1962-1964
  - Needler, 1959-1960
  - Negro achievement, 1970, undated
  - Negroes, 1945, 1954-1969, undated, (2 folders)
  - Nehru, Jawaharlal, 1956-1961, undated (Box 151)
  - Neipp, Paul C., 1963-1967, undated
  - Nelson, Steve, 1951, 1959, undated
  - New England Rally for God, Family and Country, 1963-1968
  - New Hampshire
    - History, 1959-1960, 1967, 1982, undated
    - Politics, 1964-1967, 1980, undated
    - Subversion, 1951, 1962-1965
  - New Hampshire Baptist Convention, 1960-1964
  - New Hampshire Conservative Union, 1962-1969, undated
  - New Hampshire Council of Churches, 1959-1968, undated
  - New Hampshire Profiles boycott, 1963, undated
  - New Leader, 1953-1959, undated
  - New Left, 1967-1970, undated
  - New Politics, 1965-1967, undated
  - New York Athletic Club, New York, N. Y., 1953-1970, undated, (2 folders)
  - New York blackout, 1970
  - New York City Anti-Crime Committee, 1951-1952, undated
  - New York, N. Y., elections, 1965 (Box 152)
  - New York Herald Tribune, 1951-1970, undated For additional material see Containers 230-235, Newspaper columns, (8 folders)
  - New York Times, 1957-1972, undated
  - News management, 1946-1971, undated, (2 folders) (Box 153)
  - News, slanting of, 1953-1974, 1980, undated, (2 folders)
  - Newspaper contacts and advertising rates, 1958-1959, undated
  - Newspaper Guild, 1947-1952, undated
  - Newsweek, 1960-1968, undated, (2 folders)
  - Nicaragua, 1974, 1982-1989, undated
  - Niebuhr, Reinhold, 1956-1960, 1971, undated
  - Nixon, Richard M., 1957-1982, 1988, undated, (1 folder); (3 folders) (Box 154)
  - Nixon, Russ, 1958-1962, undated
  - Noble, John H., 1930, 1947, 1954-1975, 1992, undated, (2 folders)
  - Nolde, O. Frederic, 1961-1964
  - None Dare Call It Treason, 1964
  - Noren, Loren E., 1962
  - Norman, E. Herbert, 1936-1937, 1951, 1957, undated
  - North American Newspaper Alliance, 1962, undated
  - North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO), 1957-1970 (Box 155)
  - Northeastern University, Boston, Mass., 1958, 1972-1974, 1988-1989, undated, (2 folders)
  - Northern Neighbors, 1958, 1968, undated
  - Novak, Robert See Container 93, Evans, Rowland, and Robert Novak
  - NTS (National Alliance of Russian Solidarists), 1951-1967, undated, (6 folders); (3 folders) (Box 156)
  - Nuclear tests, 1955-1968, undated
  - “N” miscellaneous, 1949-1975, 1982, undated, (3 folders)
  - Obscene literature, 1959-1963, undated, (2 folders) (Box 157)
  - Office of Economic Opportunity, 1967-1971, undated
  - Ohio
    - Joint Anti-Subversive Investigating Committee, 1951, (2 folders)
    - Miscellany, 1953-1965, undated
  - Ohio Coalition of Patriotic Societies, 1951-1960
  - Oliver, Phillip B., 1955-1956, undated
  - Oliver, Revilo P., 1961-1967, undated
  - Operation Keelhaul, 1970-1971, 1977
  - Opitz, Edmund A., 1959, 1966-1967, undated
  - Oppenheimer, J. Robert, 1949-1967, undated
  - Oswald, Lee Harvey, 1963-1975, undated For additional material see Containers 224-226, “The Strange Death of President Kennedy”
  - Otepka, Otto F., 1961-1973, undated, (3 folders) (Box 158)
  - Our American Heritage Committee, 1957-1959, 1965-1972, undated
  - Overstreet, Harry A. and Bonaro W., 1952-1971, undated
  - Oxnam, G. Bromley, 1943-1959, undated
  - “O” miscellaneous, 1952-1970, 1989, undated
  - Pageant magazine, 1958-1963, undated
  - Paine, George L., 1941, 1947, 1958, 1967, undated
  - Pakistan question, 1957, 1971, 1979 (Box 159)
  - Pan American Anti-Communist Association of New York, 1956-1957, undated
  - Panama Canal, 1964-1977, undated
  - Parcels to Russia, 1953, 1959-1963, undated
  - Paris peace talks re Vietnam War, 1968-1972
  - Parkway Village, New York, N. Y., 1952, undated
  - Passports, 1952-1963, undated, (2 folders)
  - Pasternak, Boris, 1957-1962, 1969, undated
  - Patton, James G., 1949, 1965, undated
  - Pauling, Linus, 1951-1975, undated, (3 folders); (1 folder) (Box 160)
  - Pavlov, I. P., 1956, undated
  - Peace, 1949-1972, 1982-1987, undated
  - Peace Corps, 1961-1972, undated
  - Peace fronts, 1950-1955, undated
  - Peace News, 1954-1957, 1950-1955, undated
  - Peaceful coexistence, 1954-1961, 1972, undated
  - Peacemaker Movement, 1960-1964
  - Peale, Norman Vincent, 1950-1964, 1973, undated
  - Pearson, Drew, 1954-1969, undated
  - Pearson, Roy, 1958-1960, 1966
  - Pegler, Westbrook, 1952-1957, 1963
  - Pemberton, Prentis, 1952-1966, undated
  - Penha, Armand, 1958-1962
  - Penkovsky, Oleg, 1965-1966
  - Pennington, Chester A., 1957
  - Pennington, Lee R., 1955-1966, undated
  - Pentagon, 1959-1971 (Box 161)
  - Pentagon Papers, 1971-1972, undated
  - Perlo, Victor, undated
  - Perot, H. Ross, 1969-1970, undated
  - Peru, 1965-1969, 1992
  - Pesti, Joseph, 1967
  - Petal Paper, 1968-1970, undated
  - Peterman, Ivan H., 1953
  - Peters, J., 1935, 1957, undated, (2 folders)
  - Pew, J. Howard, 1963-1964, undated
  - Phelps, Dryden L., 1952
  - Philadelphia Inquirer, 1971
  - Philby, Kim, 1967-1968
  - Philippines, 1972-1975, undated
  - Phillips, Howard, 1991
  - Pike, James A., 1957-1969, undated
  - Pink Sheet on the Left, 1971-1977, undated
  - Piper, Elsie, 1964
  - Planned Patriotism Program, 1961-1963, undated, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 162)
  - Poland, 1953-1972, 1982-1989, undated
  - Police brutality, 1965
  - Poling, Daniel A., 1949-1969, undated, (9 folders)
  - Political prisoners, 1956, undated (Box 163)
  - Political Research Project, 1955
  - Politics, 1961-1964, undated
  - Poor People's Campaign, 1968
  - Pope, Willard H., 1961, undated
  - Pornography, 1957-1973, undated, (2 folders)
  - Portsmouth Herald, 1959-1966, undated
  - Portugal, 1966-1974, undated
  - Possony, Stefan T., 1963-1972, undated
  - Powell, Adam Clayton, 1962-1972, undated (Box 164)
  - Powell, Wesley, 1958-1966, undated
  - Powers, Francis Gary, 1962-1963, undated
  - Presbyterian Church, 1953-1962, undated, (2 folders)
  - Presbyterian Life, 1959-1963
  - Press, 1959, 1966-1974, undated
  - Pride, Inc., 1970, undated
  - Princeton Seminary Bulletin, 1954, 1961, undated
  - Prisoners of War (POWs), 1954, 1964-1975, undated, (2 folders)
  - Prisons, 1957-1962
  - Progressive Labor Party, 1967-1971, undated
  - Progressive magazine, 1952, 1964, undated (Box 165)
  - Progressive Party, 1947-1953, undated
  - Prom magazine, 1969, undated
  - Propaganda, 1934, 1952-1969, 1981-1985, undated, (2 folders)
  - Property rights, 1928, 1940, 1957, 1963-1966, undated
  - Prospect House, Inc., 1971-1973, undated
  - Protestants and Other Americans United for Separation of Church and State (POAU), 1959, undated
  - Prussion, Karl, 1962-1966, undated
  - Publications and sources of information, 1952-1959, undated
  - Pueblo incident, 1961, 1968-1971, undated, (2 folders)
  - Putney School, Putney, N.H., 1954-1959, 1966-1969, undated
  - “P” miscellaneous, 1944-1979, undated, (4 folders) (Box 166)
  - Quakers, 1951, 1959, 1965-1971, undated
  - Quotations, 1942-1943, 1953-1973, 1988, undated, (4 folders)
  - “Q” miscellaneous, 1957, 1972, 1988, undated (Box 167)
  - Rabb, Maxwell M., 1946, 1952-1958, undated
  - Racial integration, 1956-1970, undated
  - Racial issues, 1951-1967, 1984, undated
  - Radio Free Europe, 1954-1972, undated, 1951-1967, 1984, undated; (2 folders)
  - Radio Liberation, 1952-1956, undated
  - Radio Liberty, 1956-1965, undated
  - Radio of Free Asia, 1968-1970, undated
  - Radio Writers Guild, 1952-1954, undated
  - Rajchman, Ludwig, 1957, undated
  - Ramparts magazine, 1966-1969
  - Rank and File Publications, 1962-1965
  - Reader's Digest, 1966-1970
  - Reagan, Ronald, 1961-1987, undated
  - Recht, Charles, 1954, undated
  - Red psychology, 1951, 1972, undated
  - Redlich, Norman, 1964-1965, undated (Box 168)
  - Reel, A. Frank, 1959
  - Regional Economic Development Institute, 1969-1970, undated, (2 folders)
  - Reid, Ogden R., 1947-1971, undated For additional material see Container 235, same heading, (2 folders)
  - Reissig, Herman F., 1954-1955, 1961-1965, undated
  - Religion
    - Communism and religion, 1954-1980, (2 folders)
    - In the Soviet Union, 1957-1970, 1982-1984, undated
    - Miscellany, 1950-1969, 1978-1991, undated, (2 folders)
  - Religious broadcasting, 1970-1973, 1979-1984 (Box 169)
  - Republican party, 1956, 1963-1977, 1987-1988, undated
  - Research Society for Creative Altruism, 1957-1959, undated
  - Responsive Environment Corp., 1967
  - Reuther, Walter, 1956-1970, undated
  - Revolutionary Action Movement (RAM), 1967-1969, undated
  - Rhee, Syngman, 1958-1960
  - Rhodesia, 1966-1975, undated, (3 folders)
  - Rice, Charles E., 1971-1974, 1987
  - Rich, Bob, 1977-1981, undated
  - Richards, Dean, 1963-1968, undated
  - Richardson, Elliot L., 1970-1972 (Box 170)
  - Riesel, Victor, 1952, 1963, undated
  - Right to work, 1955-1966, undated
  - Riots, 1954-1969, undated, (3 folders)
  - Right, 1955-1958, undated
  - Rizzo, Frank L., 1967
  - Robbins, William, 1943, 1959
  - Roberts, Arch E., 1963-1964, undated
  - Robertson, Kenneth D., Jr., 1955-1959, 1965-1970
  - Robeson, Paul, 1948-1949, 1960, undated
  - Rockefeller, Nelson A., 1959-1974, undated
  - Rockford College, Rockford, Ill., 1970-1978
  - Rockingham County (N.H.) newspapers, 1982-1989, undated, (1 folder) (Box 171)
  - Rockwell, George Lincoln, 1962-1967, undated
  - Rodney, Lester, 1968-1969, undated
  - Rogers, Donald I., 1957-1967
  - Romania, 1953-1956, 1962-1984
  - Romerstein, Herb, et al., 1960-1962, 1969
  - Romney, George, 1964-1967
  - Roosevelt, Edith K., 1962-1968, undated
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1948, 1957-1960
  - Root, E. Merrill, 1953-1959, 1966
  - Rosenberg, Allan R., 1950, 1956
  - Rosenberg, Julius and Ethel, 1950-1956, 1990, undated, (3 folders)
  - Ross, Paul L., 1955-1956
  - Roy, Ralph Lord, 1956-1966
  - Rozek, Edward J., 1966-1972, 1984-1985, undated
  - Rubin, Jerry, 1968-1971, undated (Box 172)
  - Rusk, Dean, 1961-1970, undated
  - Russell, Beecher F., 1955-1956, undated
  - Russell, Bertrand, 1956-1969, undated
  - Russia, 1952-1967, 1981, undated
  - Russian Baptists, 1954-1960, 1967, undated
  - Russian Bible Society, 1956-1963, 1972, undated
  - Russian clergy, 1956, 1963-1967, undated
  - Russian films, 1948, 1958-1961, undated
  - Rustin, Bayard, 1954-1969, undated
  - Ryder, Samuel, 1960-1962
  - Rye Area Republican Committee (N.H.), 1984-1989, undated
  - Ryker, Kenneth W., 1966-1973, undated
  - Ryskind, Morrie, 1966-1968, undated
  - “R” miscellaneous, 1920, 1948-1976, 1984-1987, undated, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 173)
  - Safeway stores, 1969
  - Salisbury, Harrison E., 1967-1969, undated
  - Samuel Adams School for Social Studies, Boston, Mass., 1944-1947, 1953-1955, undated
  - San Diego Patriotic Society, 1963-1964, undated
  - Satellites, 1959-1964, undated
  - Save American Movies (SAM), 1963-1969, undated
  - Sawyer, W. C. (“Tom”), 1958-1967
  - Saylor, Carlyle, 1963-1967, undated
  - Schirmer, Daniel Boone, 1972-1973, undated
  - Schlafly, Phyllis, 1961-1989, undated, (2 folders)
  - Schlesinger, Arthur M. (1917-2007), 1952-1967, 1974, undated (Box 174)
  - Schmitz, John G., 1971-1972
  - Schnur, Ida, 1952, undated
  - Scholarships for Freedom, 1961
  - Schools
    - Aid to schools, 1965-1966
    - Flint, Mich., 1952-1954, undated
    - General, 1951-1972, 1978-1979, undated, (2 folders)
    - New Hampshire, 1959-1963, undated, (2 folders)
    - Prayer in school, 1952-1979, undated
    - Scarsdale, N. Y., 1950-1958, 1970, undated, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 175)
    - Textbooks, 1950-1975, undated, (3 folders)
  - Schwarz, Frederick C., 1952-1979, undated For additional material see Containers 65-67, Christian Anti-Communism Crusade, (3 folders)
  - Scott, Earl C., Jr., 1959
  - Scott, Maxine, 1955-1956, undated
  - Scruton, Everett R., 1959-1960 (Box 176)
  - Seale, Bobby, 1969-1973
  - Security name check, 1957, 1965, undated
  - Seeger, Pete, 1948, 1954-1969, 1987, undated
  - Senate Foreign Relations Committee, 1955-1965, undated
  - Senate Internal Security Subcommittee, 1952-1970, undated, (5 folders)
  - Sensitivity training, 1968, undated
  - Service, John Stewart, 1956, 1971-1973, undated
  - Sex education, 1952, 1963-1975, undated, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 177)
  - Sherry, Kenneth, 1969-1970, undated
  - Shipler, Guy Emery, 1949-1959, undated
  - Shub, Anatole, 1968-1971
  - Shubow, Lawrence D., 1950, 1959, 1978-1979, undated
  - Siegel, Frank, 1954, undated
  - Siegrist, Bob, 1958-1962, undated, (2 folders)
  - Sigma Delta Chi, 1953-1974, 1989, undated, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 178)
  - Sihanouk, Norodom, 1967-1973, undated
  - Sirhan, Sirhan B., 1968-1969
  - Skousen, W. Cleon, 1960-1966, 1972, 1982-1986, undated
  - Slave labor camps, 1951-1955, 1963, 1984, undated
  - Sluis, Joost, 1962-1973, undated
  - Smith Act, 1940, 1949-1959, undated
  - Smith College, Northampton, Mass., 1956, undated
  - Smith, Donald E., 1957-1961, 1972
  - Smith, Gerald L. K., 1949, 1957, 1969-1970, undated
  - Smith, Mrs. R. Dana, 1964-1965
  - Smith, Raymond F., 1960, 1966
  - Smoot, Dan, 1956-1969, undated
  - Smut, 1959-1966, 1975, undated (Box 179)
  - Snyder, Murray, 1959-1962
  - Sobell, Morton, 1953-1957, 1965, undated
  - Sobel, Jack, 1957-1958, undated
  - Social security, 1961-1967
  - Socialism, 1928, 1956-1963, undated
  - Socialist Labor Party, 1965-1970, undated
  - Socialist Workers Party, 1948-1978, undated, (3 folders)
  - Society for Individual Freedom, 1957-1970, (2 folders)
  - Solar hoax, 1977, undated
  - Soledad Brothers, 1972, undated
  - Sokolsky, George E., 1952-1962
  - Solzhenitsyn, Aleksandr I., 1968-1975, undated
  - Sons of Liberty, 1965-1966, undated (Box 180)
  - South Africa, 1967-1990, (3 folders)
  - South Dakota Anti-Subversive League, 1959-1962
  - Southern Christian Leadership Conference (SCLC), 1964-1972, undated
  - Southern Conference Educational Fund (SCEF), 1954-1967, undated, (2 folders)
  - Soviet Affairs Notes, 1960-1961
  - Soviet dissenters, 1969-1974, 1982, undated
  - Soviet economy, 1958-1975, undated, (2 folders) (Box 181)
  - Soviet embassy, Washington, D.C., 1952, 1967-1970
  - Soviet mass propaganda media, 1959, 1965-1966
  - Soviet military, 1967-1971, undated, (2 folders)
  - Soviet Orbit Propaganda, 1956-1958, (2 folders)
  - Soviet persecution, 1959, 1968-1972, undated
  - Soviet press, 1952-1957, 1967, undated, (2 folders)
  - Soviet psychiatry, 1952-1953
  - Soviet sea power, 1959-1971, 1984, undated (Box 182)
  - Soviet secret police, 1954, 1961-1971
  - Soviet writers, 1956-1975, undated
  - Space program
    - Miscellany, 1959-1961, 1967-1971
    - Moon, 1965-1972, (2 folders)
    - USSR, 1961-1971, undated
  - Spain, 1957-1959, 1966-1970, undated
  - Speeches, 1964-1966
  - Speedie, Gordon, 1958-1959, undated
  - Speroni, Charles, 1970-1978, undated
  - Spies, 1947-1974, 1982-1992, undated, (2 folders) (Box 183)
  - Spiritual Mobilization, 1955-1959, (2 folders)
  - Spock, Benjamin, 1966-1972, undated
  - St. John, Jeffrey, 1969
  - Stalin, Joseph, 1931, 1951-1971, undated
  - Stallings, George B., Jr., 1961
  - Standard- Times, New Bedford, Mass., 1958-1959
  - Stashinskiy, Bogdan N., 1962
  - State Department, 1946, 1957-1970, 1978, undated See also Top Secret, (2 folders); (3 folders) (Box 184)
  - Steele, Peter, 1956-1957, 1964-1971, undated
  - Stevenson, Adlai E. (1900-1965), 1952-1956, 1963-1964, undated
  - Stitt, Jesse William, 1953-1956
  - Stone, I. F., 1952-1971, 1992, undated
  - Strategic Arms Limitation Talks (SALT), 1969-1979, undated (Box 185)
  - Strauss, Lewis L., 1955-1959
  - Strube, William P., 1959-1986, undated, (8 folders)
  - Struik, Dirk, 1935-1957, 1969, undated, (4 folders) (Box 186)
  - Stuart, Lyle, 1962-1968, undated
  - Student Committee for a Free China, 1967
  - Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (SNCC), 1965-1967, undated
  - Student Peace Union, 1966, undated
  - Student strikes, 1968, undated
  - Students for a Democratic Society (SDS), 1965-1972, undated, (2 folders)
  - Study group on Communism, undated (Box 187)
  - Subversive Activities Control Act of 1950, 1961-1965
  - Subversive Activities Control Board, 1951-1972, undated
  - Subversive organizations, 1957-1961, 1974, undated
  - Subversives and subversive activities, 1952-1954, 1971, undated
  - Summit conferences, 1958-1960
  - Supersonic transport (SST), 1971-1972
  - Supreme Court, 1949-1975, 1987-1992, undated, (4 folders)
  - Sustar, Jerry J., 1964-1967
  - Sutherland, William and Myrtle, 1969-1971
  - Swain, Raymond C., 1967, undated
  - Swarup, Ram, 1965-1969
  - Sweden, 1964-1973 (Box 188)
  - Sweezy, Paul M., 1955-1956, undated
  - Swift, Caroline Hyde, 1959-1962, 1972, undated
  - Symington, Stuart, 1969-1970
  - “S” miscellaneous, 1940-1945, 1951-1981, 1990, undated, (4 folders)
  - Tablet, 1958-1960
  - Talbert, Ansel E., 1959, 1966-1967, undated
  - Tarnley, Eric, 1962, 1969, undated
  - Task Force, 1959-1960, undated
  - Tax reform, 1969-1973
  - Taxes, 1959-1970, 1984, undated, (2 folders)
  - Taxi drivers, 1951-1952, undated
  - Teachers, 1948-1965, undated, (2 folders) (Box 189)
  - Teen Age Republicans, 1959, 1966-1971, undated
  - Television
    - “The Anatomy of Soviet Communism,” 1958
    - “Kraft Television Theater,” 1953-1956, undated, (2 folders)
    - Miscellany, 1952-1961, 1970-1987, undated
    - Quiz shows, 1959-1960, undated
  - Templin, Ralph, 1966-1967
  - Terminology, 1963, undated
  - Terror, 1972-1975, 1986-1990, undated
  - Thailand, 1955-1959, 1966, 1976, undated